Finding Aid for the Sandra McMullin Bennett Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Dorothy Bethurum Loomis Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0795
4.30 linear_feet
Biographical Sketch
Sandra McMullin Bennett was born and educated in Michigan. In 1988, she moved to Atlanta and in 1996 to Nashville. She joined the Greater Nashville Business and Professional Women/USA, serving two terms as President. During her tenure with this organization, she spearheaded a grassroots campaign for the passage of the Tennessee Equal Pay Remedies and Enforcement Act which was passed after two years of hard work.
She served three terms as Vice President of Legislation for the Nashville Women’s Political Caucus, lobbying for legislation affecting women and families of Tennessee. Ms. Bennett served two terms as President of the Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus and inaugurated the annual Yellow Roses Luncheon honoring women leaders in Tennessee. Beginning in 2004, she served on the Steering Committee for the Women’s Economic Summit and developed political participation workshops called “Everyday Politics for Everyday Women”. In 2004, also, she was presented with Tennessee State Resolution #955 recognizing her work on behalf of the women of the state of Tennessee
In 2006, Governor Bredesen appointed Sandra Bennett to the Board of the Tennessee Economic Council on Women, where she served six years. During her term she held the position of Secretary of the organization and its sister organization, the Women’s Economic Council Foundation, Inc. Sandra Bennett retired in 2008, and moved to Manchester, Tennessee, where she continues her interest in politics.
Scope and Content Note
Sandra McMullin Bennett’s papers are divided into five series, according to her work with various organizations: Business and Professional Women/ USA; Tennessee Economic Council on Women; Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus; Nashville Women’s Political Caucus; and Personal Papers.
Her papers include reports, summaries of legislative actions, economic summits and political workshop materials, campaign materials, and newspaper clippings. Also included is an official Proclamation of the State of Tennessee, proclaiming August 26, 2010, “Women’s Equality Day.”
Ms. Bennett was very concerned with political issues affecting the welfare of women and children in Tennessee. She was a tireless leader through the Tennessee Economic Council on Women, the Tennessee Women’s Political and the Nashville Women’s Political Caucus in encouraging, supporting, and lobbying for legislation favorable to women and children, such as equal pay and child support. Her papers reflect the enormous amount of volunteer effort expended by women such as Ms. Bennett. They do not hold elective office but nevertheless accomplish much in the political arena.
- Business and Professional Women/USA---Membership cards, 1999-2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---Certificate of Achievement (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---Membership Recruitment and Retention (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---2002-2003 Reports, Issues, and Projects (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---2004-2005 Reports, Issues, and Projects (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---2006-2007 Reports, Issues, and Projects (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Business and Professional Women/USA---Rules of Order and Installation of Officers (Box 1, Folder 7)
  The remainder of Ms. Bennett’s materials pertaining to Business and Professional Women/USA are contained in scrapbook boxes Box 10 and 11 at the end of the collection.
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“The Best and Worst State Economies for Women”, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“The White House Project”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Unmarried Women in 2006” (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Tennessee Women in Elective Office-Historical Summary”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“The Status of Women in Tennessee, 2004: Highlights” (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Why Women Should Vote”, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“A Study of Women and Political Participation”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Wages Tied to Gender Divide”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Lobbying 101” (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Tips for Successful Legislative meetings”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Tips for Connecting with Your Local Media”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---Articles about communicating with elected officials (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Deb’s 15 Rules for the Road” (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“The Need for Dialogue” (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---Articles about women with disabilities, caregivers, and preventive health issues (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---Articles about women and their financial fitness (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Why Women Having a Seat at the Table Is Not Enough” (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Benchmarking: How Nonprofits Are Adapting a Business Planning Tool for Enhanced Performance”, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Agency Strategic Plan, Idaho Women’s Commission”, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Advancing Women in the Boardroom, ION”, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Women’s Earnings”, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“The Economic Impact of Women-Owned Businesses in the United States”, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Behind the Pay Gap”, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Ten Things about Diversity and Inclusion”, Barry Salzberg (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“Why So Few?”, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Research Materials---“What Women Want Now”, Time Magazine, Oct. 26, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“The Impact of Domestic Violence on the Tennessee Economy”, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Achieving an Equally Gendered Government: The Economic Impact of Women’s Political Participation in Tennessee”, 2007 (3 Copies) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“The Economic Impact of Insufficient Preventive Healthcare for Tennessee Women” (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications--- “The Economic Status of Women in Tennessee Counties, 2012” (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“The Elios Project: Indicators of Social and Economic Well-being for Tennessee Women”, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“The Economic Impact of Wages and Earnings for Tennessee Women”, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“The Economic Impact of Women-Owned Businesses in Tennessee”, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Third Biennial Report”, 2000-2004 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Fourth Biennial Report”, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Fifth Biennial Report”, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Sixth Biennial Report”, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Publications---“Seventh Biennial Report”, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Legislative Focus and Plan of Action, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Economic Mini-Summit for Women, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Workshop Proposal, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Business and Finance Day, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women Workshop, 2009 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Economic Status of Women in Tennessee, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Economic Status of Women in Tennessee, 2011 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Economic Status of Women in Tennessee, 2012 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Economic Status of Women in Tennessee, 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Committee Reports and Activities---Women’s Economic Council Foundation, Inc. Retreat, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Organization (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Staff (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operations/ Projects (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operation/Projects (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operation/Project (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operation/Projects (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---By-laws, Member Reports (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Members (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operations/Projects (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Operations/Projects (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Council Member Notebook, 2011---Finances (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2005---The Gender Wage Gap (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2007---Issues, Initiatives, and Action (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Economic council on Women---Economic Summit, 2008 ---Comment, Collaborate, and Celebrate (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women Workshop, 2008---Planning (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women Workshop, 2008---Planning (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women Workshop, 2008---Workshop Packet (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit. 2009---Planning (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Tennessee Economic council on Women---Economic Summit, 2009---Motivate, Appreciate, Elevate (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women Workshop, 2009---Planning (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Everyday Politics for Everyday Women, 2009---Workshop Packet (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2010---Planning (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2010---Interaction, Engagement, and Results (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit. 2011---Planning (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2011---Economic Equity, Literacy, Independence, Opportunity, Stability (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2012---Planning (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit, 2013---Charting the Course (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summit---Southeastern Tennessee Women’s Summit, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Women’s Economic Council Foundation, Inc.---Research Materials (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Women’s Hall of Fame---Planning (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Women’s Hall of Fame---Event (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Women’s Economic Council Foundation, Inc.--- Foundation By-laws (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Women’s Economic Council Foundation, Inc.---Research Materials (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Tennessee Economic Council on Women---Economic Summits---Summary of Summits, 2004-2011 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Affiliation with the National Women’s Political Caucus, 2000-2007 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Research Materials, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---By-laws, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Fund raising, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Policies and Procedures (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus--- Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2007 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2008 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas. Reports, 2009 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2010 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Minutes, Agendas, Reports, 2012 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Membership, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Memphis Women’s Political Caucus, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Nashville Women’s Political Caucus, 2007-2010 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Chattanooga Women’s Political Caucus, 2007-2009 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Knoxville Women’s Political Caucus, 2008-2010 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Lobbyist, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Press Releases, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Website, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Restructuring (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Women’s Political Empowerment Workshop, Jackson, Tennessee, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Women’s Political Empowerment Workshop, Chattanooga, Tennessee, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Yellow Roses Luncheon, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Yellow Roses Luncheon, 2010 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Yellow Roses Luncheon, 2011 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Yellow Roses Luncheon, 2012 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---Planning for Campaign School (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Organization Business---When Women Run, Women Win-Campaign School (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Legislation of Interest to Women---Legislative Reports, 2003-2010 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Tennessee Women’s Political Caucus---Legislation of Interest to Women---Correspondence (e-mails) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Mandatory Joint Custody Legislation---Research Materials (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Mandatory Joint Custody Legislation---Issues, Updates (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Mandatory Joint Custody Legislation---Bill Information, Updates (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Mandatory Joint Custody Legislation---Petitions against the Bill (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Mandatory Joint Custody Legislation---Correspondence (e-mails) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Women and Voting---Research Materials (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Women and Voting---Tennessee Women and Voting (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Women and Voting---Correspondence (e-mails) (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Pay Equity Legislation---Research Materials (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Pay Equity Legislation---Publicity (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Pay Equity Legislation---Legislative Reports and Summaries (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Pay Equity Legislation---Correspondence (e-mails) (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Board of Directors---Board Manual, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Board of Directors---Board manual, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Board of Directors---Board manual, Part 1, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Board of Directors---Board Manual, Part 2, 2008 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Reports, Summaries, Correspondence, 2010 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Child Support Legislation (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Child Support Legislation (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Health Insurance Continuation Bill (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Pregnancy Resources Bill (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Women’s Day on the Hill (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Privacy Rights and Abortion (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Emergency Care for Rape Victims (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Pharmacist’s Bill (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Stalking (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Domestic Violence (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Rape of a Child (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Overtime (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Meth Bills (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Same Sex Marriage (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Nashville Women’s Political Caucus---Legislative Committee---Voter Election of Lieutenant Governor and Secretary of State (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Personal Papers---Speeches, 2004-2009 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Personal Papers---Letters to the Editor, The Tennessean, 2005-2009 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Personal Papers---Op-Eds, The Tennessean, 2009-2013 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Personal Papers---Correspondence---Incoming, Clinton-Wood (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Personal Papers---Invitations, 2008-2011 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Personal Papers---Honors, 2003-2012 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Personal Papers---Athena Awards, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Personal Awards---Athena Awards---2007, Sandra Bennett, a Nominee (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Personal Papers---Athena Awards, 2009 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Personal Papers---Honors---Photos, 1993-2011 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Personal Papers---Newspaper Clippings, 2004-2011 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Personal Papers---Political Campaigns---Bumper Stickers, Brochures, etc. (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Personal Papers---Legislative Proclamation---State of Tennessee Proclamation of Women’s Equality Day, August 26, 2010 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Scrapbook, Business and Professional Women/USA, 2002-2003 (Box 10)
- Scrapbook, Business and Professional Women/USA, 2003-2004 (Box 11)